Guide to the Peter Ackroyd Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Peter Ackroyd papers
1962-2009
GEN MSS 828
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
102.64
(130 boxes)
The Peter Ackroyd papers primarily contain research files, manuscripts, drafts, and page proofs for many of Ackroyd's novels, biographies, and historical studies, as well as related correspondence and screenplays. Also present are his appointment books, some personal papers and photographs, and personal papers of his partner Brian Michael Kuhn (1952-1994).
Ackroyd, Peter, 1949-
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 29: Restricted during the lifetime of the author. For further information consult appropriate curator.
Boxes 30, 54, 69, 92, 103, 106, 127, 128 (computer disks and laptop computer): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services.
Box 125 (audiovisual material): Access to original audiovisual recordings is restricted. Reference copies may be requested through Access Services.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from R. A. Gekoski Booksellers on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1994-2005, 2010; gift of Peter Ackroyd, 2005-2011. For further information see Collections Contents list.
Existence and Location of Copies
Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Peter Ackroyd (1949- )
Peter Ackroyd, British novelist, critic, poet, biographer, and essayist, was born in London on October 5, 1949, and raised in East Acton. Educated at Saint Benedict's School, Ealing, he graduated from Clare College, Cambridge, in 1971 with a degree in English, and studied at Yale University under a Mellon Foundation fellowship from 1971 to 1973. Ackroyd was the literary editor of the Spectator from 1973 to 1977, and managing editor from 1977 to 1981. He is the author of more than a dozen novels, four books of poetry, and over twenty works of non-fiction, including studies of the cities of London and Venice, the authors Blake, Chaucer, Dickens, Eliot, Poe, Pound, and Shakespeare, and the cultures of Ancient Egypt, Greece, and Rome. Ackroyd has won numerous literary awards, was named Commander of the Order of the British Empire (CBE) in 2003, and elected to membership in the American Academy of Arts and Sciences in 2006.
His partner Brian Michael Kuhn was born in New York on June 26, 1952. Ackroyd and Kuhn met while Ackroyd was studying in the United States; afterward Kuhn moved to England, living in London and Devon from 1973 until his death from an AIDS-related illness in 1994.
Scope and Contents
The Peter Ackroyd Papers primarily contain research files, manuscripts, drafts, and page proofs for many of his novels, biographies, and historical studies, as well as related correspondence and screenplays. Also present are his appointment books, some personal papers and photographs, and papers related to his partner Brian Michael Kuhn.
Arrangement
Organized into sixteen groupings: I. February 1994 Acquisition. II. April 1997 Acquisition. III. August 2000 Acquisition. IV. June 2005 Acquisition. V. July 2005 Acquisition. VI. November 2005 Acquisition. VII. March 2006 Acquisition. VIII. November 2006 Acquisition. IX. January 2007 Acquisition. X. May 2007 Acquisition. XI. November 2008 Acquisition. XII. February 2010 Acquisition. XIII. March 2010 Acquisition. XIV. April 2010 Acquisition. XV. September 2010 Acquisition. XVI. September 2011 Acquisition.
Material within this collection has been organized by acquisition reflecting the fact that the collection has been acquired in increments over time. Researchers should note that material within each acquisition overlaps with or relates to material found in other acquisitions (e.g., correspondence, writings, and personal papers can be found in all groupings). In order to locate all relevant material within this collection, researchers should consult each acquisition described in the Collection Contents section.
Researchers should also note that similar material can be arranged differently in each acquisition, depending on how the material was organized when it was received by the library.
Authors, English -- 20th Century -- Archives; English literature -- 20th Century; England -- Civilization; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Electronic documents; Sound recordings; Storage devices (computer equipment); Ackroyd, Peter, 1949-; Kuhn, Brian Michael, 1952-1994
- February 1994 Acquisition, Series I; 26.67 linear feet (29 boxes, including 14 computer disks)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from R. A. Gekoski Booksellers on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1994.
  General note
  Former call number: Uncat MS Vault 706
  Arrangement
  Organized under five headings: Correspondence, Writings, Appointment Books, Reviews and Clippings, and Miscellaneous.
  Scope and Contents
  Contains correspondence, appointment calendars, notes, photographs, printed material, and writings by, to, or relating to Peter Ackroyd. Includes letters from John Ashbery, Anthony Powell, Kathleen Raine, Edmund White, and others; writings, including Chatterton, typescripts, various drafts; Dickens, typescripts, various drafts; and other works by Peter Ackroyd.
  - Correspondence
    - Unsorted correspondence, 17 (Box 1)
  - Writings
    - Novels, plays, and biographies (Box 2)
      - Albion: the Origins of the English Imagination
        - Drafts, 7 (Box 2)
      - Chatterton
        - Notebooks, 5 (Box 2)
        - Drafts, 9 (Box 2)
        - Drafts, 2 (Box 3)
        - Notes, research, 2 (Box 3)
      - Dickens
        - Drafts, 11 (Box 3)
        - Drafts, 15 (Box 4)
        - Drafts, 15 folders, including 14 computer disks (Box 5)
          Conditions Governing Access
          Computer disks are restricted. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services.
          Uncat MSS 706 Disks #1-14: Dickens I-XL
        - Drafts, 17 (Box 6)
        - Proofs, 18 (Box 7)
        - Research material, 4 (Box 7)
        - Research material, 19 (Box 8)
        - Research material and notes, 19 (Box 9)
        - Research material, 18 (Box 10)
        - Research material, 21 (Box 11)
        - Research material, 8 (Box 12)
        - Miscellaneous material, 6 (Box 12)
      - English Music
        - Notebooks, 3 (Box 12)
        - Notebooks, 2 (Box 13)
        - Typescripts, 3 (Box 13)
        - Manuscripts, 7 (Box 13)
      - First Light
        - Notebooks, 6 (Box 13)
        - Notebooks (Box 14)
        - Typescripts, 4 (Box 14)
        - Notes, 2 (Box 14)
        - Typescripts, 12 (Box 14)
        - Typescripts, 6 (Box 15)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
      - The Great Fire of London, typescripts, 5 (Box 15)
      - Hawksmoor
        - Notebooks, 7 (Box 15)
        - Notebooks, 4 (Box 16)
        - Typescripts, 6 (Box 16)
        - Typescript, final, 6 (Box 16)
        - Carbon copy, 3 (Box 16)
        - Carbon copy, 4 (Box 17)
      - House of Doctor Dee
        - Notebooks, 3 (Box 17)
        - Drafts, 11 (Box 17)
        - Drafts, 7 (Box 18)
      - Last Testament of Oscar Wilde
        - Notebooks, 5 (Box 18)
        - Notes (Box 18)
        - Drafts, 6 (Box 18)
      - T. S. Eliot
        - Notes (Box 19)
        - Notebooks, 8 (Box 19)
        - Typescripts, 3 (Box 19)
        - Photocopies, 9 (Box 20)
      - Ezra Pound and his World
        - Notebook, 5 (Box 20)
    - Poetry and essays
      - Diversions of Purley and Other Poems, 2 (Box 21)
      - Dressing Up: Transvestism and Drag: the History of an Obsession, 4 (Box 21)
      - Language: The Fall of Man (Box 21)
      - Notes for a New Culture: an Essay on Modernism (Box 21)
    - Unidentified
      - Papers, 5 (Box 21)
      - Photographs (Box 21)
      - Notebooks, 2 (Box 21)
    - Writings of others
      - Davies, Andrew, "House of Cards" (Box 21)
      - Drane, David, "Marlarge" (Box 21)
      - Flanagan, John and Andrew McCullock, "Sleepers" (Box 22)
      - Gooch, Brad, "The City Poet" (Box 22)
      - Howard, Lee, "Crossing the Frozen River" (Box 22)
      - Martin, Troy Kennedy, "Edge of Darkness" (Box 22)
      - McGuiness, Frank, "The Beautiful Lie" (Box 22)
      - Orne, Eadric, "PR 2947-M3" (Box 22)
      - Sinclair, Iain, "Downriver", 3 (Box 22)
      - Smith, Robert, "Hawksmoor," screenplay, 2 (Box 22)
  - Appointment books
    - 1981-1985, 5 (Box 22)
    - 1986-1992, 7 (Box 23)
  - Reviews and clippings
    - Chatterton, 4 (Box 23)
    - Dickens, 3 folders (Box 23)
    - Dickens, 4 folders (Box 24)
    - The House of Doctor Dee (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous, 14 (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous, 16 (Box 25)
    - Miscellaneous, 7 (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Publicity material (Box 26)
    - Ackroyd's mother's reminiscences, 2 (Box 26)
    - Ackroyd's mother's address book (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous clippings (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 27)
    - English Music, corrected editor's proof (Box 28)
  - Restricted Material
    Restricted during the lifetime of the author. For further information consult appropriate curator.
    - Restricted papers. For further information consult the curator. (Box 29)
  - Computer disks
    - Computer disks (Uncat MS Vault 706 disks #1-14) (Box 30)
      Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services.
- April 1997 Acquisition, Series II; 15.80 linear feet (24 boxes, including 23 computer disks)
  Purchased from R. A. Gekoski Booksellers on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1997.
  Former call number: Uncat MS Vault 789
  Contains correspondence, including letters from Brian Kuhn, Valerie Eliot, Michael Moorcock, Michael Horowitz and others; manuscripts, and research material relating to Blake, Dan Leno and the Limehouse Golem, Milton in America, and T. S. Eliot; personal papers; photographs and printed material, including reviews.
  - Card files of Oscar Wilde, Ezra Pound, and Charles Dickens, partial ms. of "The House," "This is the true story of Elizabeth Barton..." partial ms., notes on English Music, partial mss. of A Tale of the Expected, ms. of Albion, 14 folders, including 5 computer disks (Box 31)
    Uncat MS Vault 789 Disk #1: untitled
    Uncat MS Vault 789 Disk #2: Albion Chapters XIII-XVI
    Uncat MS Vault 789 Disk #3: Dickens XL-
    Uncat MS Vault 789 Disk #4: XIII-XVI
    Uncat MS Vault 789 Disk #5: XIX-XXI
  - Card files on T. S. Eliot, Charles Dickens, Oscar Wilde, 7 (Box 32)
  - Life of Thomas More, manuscript, 15 (Box 33)
  - Life of Thomas More, manuscript, 5 (Box 34)
  - Card files on Charles Dickens, T. S. Eliot (Box 35)
  - Photocopies of T.S. Eliot correspondence, notes on Eliot, Ackroyd correspondence, 1982-1983; 9 (Box 36)
  - T.S. Eliot correspondence, notes on Eliot, photocopies of poems by Eliot, card files on Eliot, Ackroyd correspondence, 1982-1984; 8 (Box 37)
  - Notes on Dickens, photographs, Ackroyd correspondence, 1984-1994; 1 (Box 38)
    Uncat MS Vault 789 Disk #6: Chapters 5-8
  - Photographs, correspondence, 1994-1997; 44 (Box 39)
  - Reviews and publicity on Ackroyd's work, 34 (Box 40)
  - Manuscripts of Dan Leno, Elizabeth Cree, notes on Elizabeth Cree, Ackroyd's review of Juliet Barker's "The Brontes", 18 folders, including 2 computer disks (Box 41)
    Uncat MS Vault 789 Disk #7: untitled
    Uncat MS Vault 789 Disk #8: Leno novel 1-17
  - Photocopies on Blake, notes on Blake, photocopies of Blake manuscript, 14 (Box 42)
  - Articles on Blake, notes on Blake, 13 (Box 43)
  - Articles on Blake, notes on Blake, photocopy of Of Geese, Mallards and Drakes by Selby Wittingham, photocopy of An Historical Account of the Will of J. M. W. Turner by Selby Wittingham, 35 (Box 44)
  - Milton manuscript, notes on Milton, photocopy of "An outline for a feature film by David Thomas and Michael Hurst, Morton of Merrymount", 43 (Box 45)
  - Copy of The New and Complete British Traveller, speech notes, magazine articles, The Last Testament of Oscar Wilde partial ms., 2 (Box 46)
  - Brian Kuhn's financial records, correspondence, travel brochures, copy of Around the House by David Schweitzer and Martina Finch, photographs, financial records, 1993 appointment book, photocopies of Blake material, copy of Russell, The Journal of the Bertrand Russell Archives 2, (New Series, no. 1, 1992), copy of Proposals for Land in the Vicinity of St.-George-in-the-East a report by Blashfield and Peto, copy of a background report on "Dyer's Court", 1988-1995; 12 folders (Box 47)
  - Notes and articles on Blake, reviews on Ackroyd's work, dust jacket proofs of Blake, correspondence, circa 1995; 7 (Box 48)
  - Dickens notes, card files on Dickens, correspondence, 1987-1989; 2 folders (Box 49)
  - Milton in America manuscript, notes and articles on Milton, card files on Blake and Dickens, 13 (Box 50)
  - Page proofs of Blake, dust jacket proof of Blake, notes on Blake, card files on Blake, ms. of Blake, articles on Blake, correspondence, photograph of "The Felpham rummer", of Blake, version of speech given at Tate gallery, circa 1993; 29 folders, including 1 computer disk (Box 51)
    Uncat MS Vault 789 Disk #9: Blake
  - Notes on Blake, Blake ms., page proofs of Blake, page proofs of The poems of William Blake. Correspondence, photocopy of "The Felpham rummer: A New Angel and Immoral Drink attributed to William Blake" relating to photograph in box 21, articles by Ackroyd on Blake, circa 1990-1993; 11 (Box 52)
  - Manuals and system software for Apple computers, 4 folders, including 14 computer disks (Box 53)
    Uncat MS Vault 789 Disk #10: untitled
    Uncat MS Vault 789 Disks #11-23: commercial software; files may not be requested.
  - Computer disks
    - Computer disks (Uncat MS Vault 789 disks #1-23) (Box 54)
- August 2000 Acquisition, Series III; 14.21 linear feet (15 boxes, including 2 computer disks)
  Purchased from R. A. Gekoski Booksellers on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2000.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 58.
  Organized under five headings: Writings, Writings by others, Published reviews and articles, Correspondence, and Other papers.
  - Writings
    - The Life of Thomas More
      Typed and handwritten ms. including notebooks, reviews and related material.
      [The # sign represents a numbering sequence on the original binders]
      - #1-2, 5 (Box 55)
      - #2, 5 (Box 55)
      - #3, 7 (Box 55)
      - #4, 4 (Box 56)
      - #5, 4 (Box 56)
      - #6, 4 (Box 56)
      - #7, 4 (Box 56)
      - #8, 3 (Box 57)
      - #9, 4 (Box 57)
      - #10, 5 (Box 57)
      - #11, 4 (Box 57)
      - #12, 6 (Box 58)
      - #13, 4 (Box 58)
      - #14, 4 (Box 58)
      - #15, 4 (Box 58)
      - #16, 4 (Box 59)
      - Unsorted handwritten and typed ms. including notes and other related material for the book, 18 (Box 59)
    - London, the Biography
      Loose and unsorted manuscripts, proofs, various research material and related notes. File box letter designations were assigned by the library when accessioned.
      - File Box "A", 5 (Box 60)
      - File Box "B", 5 (Box 60)
      - File Box "C", 4 (Box 60)
      - File Box "D", 4 (Box 60)
      - File Box "E", 4 (Box 61)
      - File Box "F", 4 (Box 61)
      - File Box "G", 4 (Box 61)
      - File Box "H", 4 (Box 61)
      - Edited typescript copies, 12 (Box 62)
      - Edited typescript copies, 9 (Box 63)
    - The Plato Papers
      - Manuscripts, proofs, original notes, research papers and holograph notes, 14 (Box 64)
    - The Trial of Elizabeth Cree
      - First, second, and final proofs with related correspondence, 7 (Box 65)
    - Dickens: A Play
      - Holograph notes, edited typescript, assorted notes, 9 folders (Box 65)
    - Milton In America
      - Proofs, edited manuscripts, notes, and related correspondence, 11 folders, including 2 computer disks (Box 66)
        Uncat MSS 58 Disks #1-2: untitled
      - Miscellaneous and unsorted edited drafts, handwritten manuscripts, photocopies, clippings, note cards and jacket covers, 1990-1999; 7 (Box 66)
      - Miscellaneous and unsorted edited drafts, handwritten manuscripts, photocopies, clippings, note cards and jacket covers, 1990-1999; 17 (Box 67)
  - Writings by others
    - Green, Andrew. Blake, typescript (Box 68)
    - Watson, Ben. Art, Class and Cleavage, loose manuscripts, correspondence, 1997; 3 folders (Box 68)
  - Published reviews and articles
    - Various clippings and articles from magazines newspapers and journals, 1998-1999 (Box 68)
  - Correspondence
    - Incoming personal and professional letters, cards, and faxes, 1998-2000; 4 (Box 68)
  - Other papers
    - Address Book (Box 68)
    - " Mr. Peter Ackroyd", 1999 August 18; GENMSS828_0001; 1; 00:03:57 (Box 68, Item barcode 39002102339448)
      The tape appears to show some type of medical screening of the patient listed, Peter Ackroyd.
    - Notebook (Box 68)
    - X-rays (Box 68)
  - Computer disks
    - Computer disks (Uncat MS 58 disks #1-2) (Box 69)
- June 2005 Acquisition, Series IV; 21.46 linear feet (24 boxes, including 20 computer disks)
  Purchased from R. A. Gekoski Booksellers on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2005.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 786.
  Organized under two headings: Writings, and Personal Papers.
  Contains correspondence; writings, including notes and research materials; photographs; personal papers, including diaries and papers related to honors received by Peter Ackroyd.
  - Writings
    - Albion: the Origins of the English Imagination
      - Chapter 1, Anglo Saxons, 4 (Box 70)
      - Chaucer notes from English Imagination 1, 2 (Box 70)
      - III, 2 folders (Box 70)
      - IV: Renaissance Chapter 3, 4 (Box 70)
      - VI: English Imagination, miscellaneous works on Renaissance, 3 (Box 70)
      - VII, 4 folders (Box 70)
      - VIII, 3 folders (Box 71)
      - IX, 4 folders (Box 71)
      - X, 4 folders (Box 71)
      - XI, 4 folders (Box 71)
      - XII, 5 folders (Box 71)
      - XIII, 3 folders (Box 72)
      - Research, 3 (Box 72)
      - Miscellaneous, 15 (Box 72)
      - Miscellaneous, 11 (Box 73)
      - Notebook (Box 73)
      - Miscellaneous, 5 (Box 73)
      - Miscellaneous, 18 (Box 74)
      - Miscellaneous, 17 (Box 75)
      - Miscellaneous, 6 (Box 76)
    - Clerkenwell Tales
      - Notebooks, 6 (Box 76)
      - Penny's, 3 (Box 76)
      - Miscellaneous, 5 (Box 76)
      - Proofs, 2 (Box 76)
    - The Lambs of London
      - Notebooks, 5 (Box 77)
      - Miscellaneous, 3 (Box 77)
      - Author's proofs, 3 (Box 77)
      - Mr. H.W., 3 (Box 77)
    - Shakespeare (Box 77)
    - Space (Box 77)
    - Turner notebook (Box 77)
    - Turner (Box 77)
    - London: the Biography
      - Popular follies, prostitution, 3 (Box 78)
      - Saints, churches, London Society, proceeding, history of London, 3 (Box 78)
      - St. Giles, Story of London, Dickens, 3 (Box 78)
      - Themes, 4 (Box 78)
      - Historical periods, 4 (Box 78)
      - History, 4 (Box 79)
      - General, 4 (Box 79)
      - Archeological digs, 5 (Box 79)
      - X, 3 folders (Box 79)
      - Fitter Lane, 4 (Box 79)
      - XII - XIII, 7 (Box 80)
      - XIV, 4 folders (Box 80)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 80)
      - Research (Box 80)
      - Third proof, 3 (Box 80)
      - Miscellaneous, 4 (Box 80)
    - Chaucer
      - Notes from London, 4 (Box 80)
      - Social background, 3 (Box 81)
      - Criticism essays in various subjects, 3 (Box 81)
      - Criticism; general introduction; specific themes, 3 (Box 81)
      - Miscellaneous, 5 (Box 81)
      - Uncorrected proof, 3 (Box 81)
      - Miscellaneous, 3 (Box 81)
      - Miscellaneous, 4 (Box 82)
    - The Fall of Troy, 4 (Box 82)
    - [Troy notebook], 5 (Box 82)
    - [Dickens, miscellaneous], 4 (Box 82)
    - Dorling Kindersley, 2 (Box 82)
    - Dorling Kindersley, 2 (Box 83)
    - Miscellaneous, 13 (Box 83)
    - Reviews written by Ackroyd, 3 (Box 83)
    - Reviews written by Ackroyd (Box 84)
    - Shakespeare: a Biography
      - Miscellaneous, 6 (Box 84)
      - Notes, 2 (Box 84)
      - Typescript, 4 (Box 84)
    - Miscellaneous, 15 folders, including 16 computer disks (Box 85)
      Uncat MSS 786 Disk #1: untitled
      Uncat MSS 786 Disk #2: Blake
      Uncat MSS 786 Disks #3-10: London
      Uncat MSS 786 Disk #11: essays & reviews & Callow
      Uncat MSS 786 Disk #12: plays & reviews
      Uncat MSS 786 Disk #13: lectures + reviews (library copy)
      Uncat MSS 786 Disk #14: MCD
      Uncat MSS 786 Disk #15: untitled
      Uncat MSS 786 Disk #16 commercial software for Apple computer; files may not be requested.
    - Liberty: Peter Ackroyd's Romantics, 8 (Box 86)
  - Personal papers
    - Personal papers, 12 folders, including 4 computer disks (Box 86)
      Uncat MSS 786 Disk #17: New York & Chicago
      Uncat MSS 786 Disk #18: Minerva II, 2003
      Uncat MSS 786 Disk #19: Family Folders 1-5
      Uncat MSS 786 Disk #20: untitled (photographs)
    - Personal papers, 6 (Box 87)
    - The Fleet Bridge (Box 87)
    - Personal papers, 13 (Box 87)
    - Personal papers, 20 (Box 88)
    - Personal papers, 20 (Box 89)
    - Ideas, 44 Albion (Box 89)
    - Betlin's Alibi (Box 89)
    - Appointment books, 1995, 2; s (Box 89)
    - Appointment books, 1996-2004, 9 (Box 90)
    - Notebook (Box 90)
    - "Leading Hotels of the World" (Box 90)
    - [Painting] (Box 91)
    - Personal papers, 3 (Box 91)
  - Computer disks
    - Computer disks (Uncat MSS 786 disks #1-20) (Box 92)
- July 2005 Acquisition, 2002-2003; Series V; 0.63 linear feet (2 boxes)
  Gift of Peter Ackroyd, 2005.
  Former call number Uncat MSS 786.
  - Albion: the Origins of the English Imagination, proofs and galleys, corrected, 14 (Box 93)
  - Albion: the Origins of the English Imagination, proofs and galleys, corrected, 4 (Box 94)
- November 2005 Acquisition, 2003-2004; Series VI; 0.42; (1 box)
  Former call number Uncat MSS 827.
  - Clerkenwell Tales, page proofs, corrected, 3 (Box 95)
- March 2006 Acquisition, 2004; Series VII; 0.21; (1 box)
  Gift of Peter Ackroyd, 2006.
  Former call number Uncat MSS 854.
  - Chaucer, page proofs, corrected, 2 (Box 96)
- November 2006 Acquisition, 2004-2005; Series VIII; 1; (1 box)
  Former call number Uncat MSS 910.
  - Chaucer, page proofs, corrected, 2 (Box 97)
  - Shakespeare: the Biography, page proofs, corrected, 9 (Box 97)
- January 2007 Acquisition, 2005; Series IX; 0.42; (1 box)
  Gift of Peter Ackroyd, 2007.
  Former call number Uncat MSS 922.
  - J. M. W. Turner: page proofs, 5 (Box 98)
- May 2007 Acquisition, 2005-2006; Series X; 0.42; (1 box)
  Former call number Uncat MSS 946.
  - Lambs of London, page proofs, 4 (Box 99)
- November 2008 Acquisition, Series XI; 0.42; (1 box)
  Gift of Peter Ackroyd, 2008.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 1049.
  - Fall of Troy: a Novel, copyedited typescript and page proofs, 6 folders (Box 100)
- February 2010 Acquisition, Series XII; 0.63 linear feet (3 boxes, including 1 computer disk)
  Gift of Peter Ackroyd, 2010.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 1229.
  - Poe: a Life Cut Short, typescript, proofs, 5 folders, including 1 computer disk (Box 101)
    Uncat MSS 1229 Disk #1: NAT/DDAY Spring '09
  - Poe: a Life Cut Short, proofs, 2 (Box 102)
  - Computer disks
    - Computer disk (Uncat MSS 1229 disk #1) (Box 103)
- March 2010 Acquisition, Series XIII; 1.42 linear feet (3 boxes, including 1 computer disk)
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 1234.
  - Thames: the Biography, proofs, 14 (Box 104)
  - Newton, proofs, 4 folders, including 1 computer disk (Box 105)
    Uncat MSS 1234 Disk #1: Newton text + pics files
  - Computer disks
    - Computer disk (Uncat MSS 1234 Disk #1) (Box 106)
- April 2010 Acquisition, Series XIV; 0.42; (1 box)
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 1240.
  - Thames: the Biography, galleys, 5 (Box 107)
- September 2010 Acquisition, 1989-2008; Series XV; 17.09 linear feet (21 boxes, including 21 computer disks and 1 laptop computer)